（フィー）
ハチ 仕分けのほう よろしくね
Okay, Hachi, get started
on the sorting work.
I'll come right down to help out
once I'm done with the paperwork.
（フィー）手続き 終わったら
すぐに私も手伝うから
I copy.
（ハチマキ）アイ コピー
ったく 帰った早々 仕事 仕事って
Damn it, they put us to work
right after we got back...
（タナベ）
十分 休んだじゃないですか
Come on, you got
plenty of rest.
In a hospital bed.
（ハチマキ）病院でな
（タナベ）でも いいことも
あったんじゃないですか？
It wasn't all bad,
though, right?
I don't wanna play tag
with ninjas ever again.
（ハチマキ）
忍者と追いかけっこなんざ―
二度とごめんだね
No, that that.
I meant the girl in the hospital.
（タナベ）そうじゃなくて
病院の子のほうですよ
Yo.
（男性１）よう
（タナベ）ん？
（男性１）
テクノーラさん 休暇は終わりか？
Hey, Technora guys.
Vacation's over?
（ハチマキ）
ああ 早速 こき使われてるよ
Yep, and they didn't waste any time
in working us like dogs again.
（男性２）
しかし すんげえ拾ってきたな
Still, you guys came back with a huge haul.
That's Toy Box for ya.
さすが ToyBox(トイボックス)
は？
She's Fee-san's ship, right?
（男性２）
フィーさんの船だろ？ これ
はい
Right.
She's the best there is when it comes to
piloting. Giving retrieval instructions, too.
（男性２）
ピカイチだよな 操船も回収指示も
I hear she even turned down Vega
when they tried to scout her.
（男性１）ベガ社からのスカウトも
断ったんだって？
Yeah, I heard, I heard.
（男性２）ああ 聞いた 聞いた
フィーさんって
結構 有名人だったんだ
I didn't know Fee-san
was such a celebrity.
Yeah. In this biz, nobody can
even come close to Fee.
ああ この業界じゃ
飛びっ切り優秀だよ フィーは
Of course, it doesn't look like the top brass
have caught on to that little fact.
もっとも 上の連中は ちっとも
分かってないみたいだけどな
♪～
♪そして人は時空(とき)を
越えた夢を見る
Soshite hito wa toki wo koeta yume wo miru
And people dream dreams that transcend time.
seijyaku no umi ni idakarete
Held in the depths of the sea.
♪静寂の宇宙(うみ)に抱かれて
♪鳥や雲を見上げては
tori ya kumo wo miagete wa
As they look up at the stars and clouds.
hakanai inochi moyashita ikusen no asa ni
It set their ephemeral souls on fire on a thousand mornings.
♪儚(はかな)い生命(いのち)燃やした
♪幾千の朝に
hikari ga mukau basho he habataku darou
I bet they're taking right to where the light is headed.
♪光が向かう場所へ
♪羽ばたくだろう
daichi wo ima tori yoku kette
Now kickoff from the ground like a bird.
♪願いを放つ時は今
hatenaki yume wo noseta furontia he
Off into the frontier that is carrying boundless dreams.
♪果てなき夢を乗せた
♪フロンティアへ
♪遠く遠く Dive in the Sky
tooku tooku dive in the sky
Farther and farther dive in the sky.
Phase 8
A Place to Cling to
Surely neither Vega or Ogorico are quite
that hard pressed for human resources...
Mind if I sit here?
（フィー）ここ いい？
（ドルフ）ん？
お久しぶり
Long time, no see.
（社員１）何だ？ あの女
Who's the woman?
She's with Half Section,
isn't she?
（社員２）半課のやつだろ？
I bet she's trying to suck up
to the division manager.
事業部長に
こび売ってんじゃないの？
（社員１）ケッ
I ran into Chad
on the moon.
月で チャドに会ったわ
経理課に配属になってた
He'd been assigned to
Accounting Section.
これ 預かってきたんだけど
He asked me to keep this for him.
He said he found it when he moved.
引っ越しで見つけたんだって
Really takes you back,
doesn't it?
懐かしいわね
But it looked like Chad wasn't getting
along as well as he did back then.
でも チャド あのころみたいには
いかないみたい
That's right.
Things aren't the same now.
（ドルフ）
そうだ あのころとは違う
（フィー）ん？
ちょうどよかった
君に話しておきたいことがある
Actually, you came at a good time.
There's something I want to discuss with you.
あっ…
All right, we'll leave the arrangements for
the welcome reception to you, Lavie.
（ゲイハート）
じゃ 歓迎会の仕切りは―
ラビィ君に任せるということで
（ラビィ）
はっ お任せください
Yes, sir! Leave everything
to me, sir!
We're only bringing you in to make sure
the guest is kept happy,
（社員）接待のためだけに
君を置いているんだから―
...so we don't want to see
any slip-ups.
間違いのないように
Of course not!
そりゃあ もう デヘヘヘッ… ん？
（ラビィ）あちっ… って
どうすりゃいいのよ この場合
Ouch!
What am I supposed to do
in a situation like this?!
（ハチマキ）
何言ってんだよ ばかばかしい
What're you saying?
What a load of crap.
ネタ 振ってんな ったく…
Don't go around
spreading rumors.
It's the truth, I swear!
Fee and the
division manager were sitting all alone!
本当なんだって
フィーと事業部長が２人っきりで…
リストラの相談でも
してたんじゃねえの？
You sure they weren't talking over
downsizing plans or something?
（課長）ええっ！？
Downsizing would be
Personnel Section, right?
リストラなら 人事だろ？
Why would the division manager himself talk
to a Half Section team leader about that?
わざわざ 事業部長様が
半課の主任に伝えるか？
半課って言うなよ プライドねえな
Don't call us Half Section!
Where's your pride?
I couldn't hear what they were saying,
but she handed him a thin piece of paper.
話は聞こえなかったけど―
薄っぺらな
紙みたいな物を渡してた
Paper?
Like a letter?
紙って 手紙ですか？
In this day and age?
A disk, maybe?
今どき？ ディスクとか？
（課長）写真
A picture!
何かのチケット
（ユーリ）お金
A ticket to something!
Money?
お金？ 手切れ金！
Money...?
Separation money?!
（課長）
あの２人って つきあってたの！？
Those two were seeing
each other?!
Of course not! Fee-san is married
and even has a son!
（タナベ）
そんなわけないじゃないですか
フィーさん
結婚して 子供もいますよ
So she's having an affair? This isn't...
不倫ってこと？ マズいな
だから 違いますって！
You've got it all wrong!
What kind of relationship
do they have, then?!
じゃあ どういう関係なのよ
うわっ ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
（エーデル）時間ですので
帰らせていただきます
It's quitting time, so I'm going to
call it a day, if you don't mind.
（ラビィ）はあ
Okay...
（エーデル）
それでは お先に失礼します
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Good work today...
（タナベ）お疲れさまでした
I must admit,
it does seem odd.
確かに おかしいですね
Yeah, people our age
spying like this.
（ハチマキ）いい年して
こんなことやってる俺たちがな
やっぱり 手切れ金じゃ…
It's got to be a
separation payment.
違いますよ
It is not! Fee-sama is married
and even has a...
フィーさんは
結婚して 子供もいるんですから
そういうのって
関係ねえんじゃねえの？
Stuff like that doesn't have
anything to do with it.
そういうのって
関係ねえんじゃねえの？
はい？
Excuse me?
ほんとに好きになったら―
When you're in love, stuff like kids or husbands
are the last thing on your mind, right?
ほんとに好きになったら―
子供とか旦那とか
すっ飛んじまうもんだろ？
Are you speaking
from experience?
経験談ですか？
一般論だよ
I'm just speaking
in general.
Then are you saying that Fee-san
is having an affair, Senpai?
じゃあ 先輩は フィーさんが
不倫してるって言うんですね？
What are you so mad about?!
These things happen.
何 怒ってんだよ
そういうこともあるって話…
もう いいです！
I've had enough!
私一人でも フィーさんの無実を
証明してみせます！
I'm gonna go prove Fee-san's innocence!
By myself if I have to!
Hey! Where are you going?! Tanabe!
（ハチマキ）
おい！ どこ行くんだよ タナベ
（課長）どうしよう ラビィちゃん
What should we do, Lavie-chan?
Leave it to me, Chief. Now is the time
to put my networking skills to use.
お任せください 課長
今こそ 私の人脈を使うときです
（ハチマキ）
ちょっと待てって おい
Hey, wait up,
damn it!
（タナベ）どうしてですか？
Why should I?
Won't asking the division manager directly be the fastest way to find out?
事業部長に直接 聞いたほうが
早いじゃありませんか
（ハチマキ）アホか？ お前は
- What are you, an idiot?!
As if he'd tell you the truth!
正直に話すわけないだろ？
（クレア）どいてくれる？
（ハチマキ）ん… あ あっ
Would you mind
stepping aside?
Um, you're...
ああ えーっと…
It's Claire Rondo of Control Section,
Tanabe Ai-san of Half Section.
（クレア）
管制課のクレア･ロンドよ
半課の田名部(たなべ) 愛(あい)さん
デブリ課です！
It's Debris Section!
ここは管制課よ
用がないなら 半課に帰りなさい
This is Control Section. If you don't have
any business here, go back to Half Section.
（タナベ）用なら あります
We have business here, all right! We're here
to ask the division manager something!
事業部長に
聞きたいことがあるんです
H-Hey!
おっ おい
（クレア）不倫したかどうか？
（タナベ･ハチマキ）えっ？
Ask him if he's been having
an affair?
あれだけ大声 出してればね
You were speaking
rather loudly.
You really shouldn't stick your nose
into the private matters of strangers.
他人のプライバシーに
口を挟むもんじゃないわよ
Understand, Tanabe-san
the rookie?
半人前のタナベさん
（タナベ）他人じゃありません
We're not strangers.
What are you, then?
Don't try to tell me you're friends.
（クレア）じゃあ 何？
仲間とか言わないでよ？
What's wrong
with that?
（タナベ）いけませんか？
（ハチマキ）おい やめろって
Come on, cut it out.
先輩は黙っててください
You stay out of this, Senpai!
先輩？
"Senpai"?
It sounds like you think you're still
a student in an after-school club.
学生のサークル気分が
抜けてないみたいね
A company isn't
a family.
会社は家族じゃないのよ
そんな割り切り方 愛がありません
There's no love in coldly
dividing people up like that!
（クレア）
フンッ 今からでも遅くないわ
シスターでも目指したら？
You know, it's not too late. Why don't
you try to become a nun or something?
（チェンシン）アッハハハ…
That's one interesting girl.
She actually held her own against Claire?
（チェンシン）面白い子じゃないか
クレアと互角に言い合えるなんて
She doesn't have
the brains for that.
（ハチマキ）
あいつに そんな頭はねえよ
All she's got in her head is that
idiotic, superficial notion of love.
愛 愛って バカみたいに
上っ面 なぞってるだけだよ
（チェンシン）ふーん
（ハチマキ）
あのあと 押しとどめるのだって…
Afterwards, she said she'd try
to keep it under control.
ああっ くそ！ また負けた
Crap, I lost again!
So, did you talk to Claire
about anything?
（チェンシン）
…で クレアとは何か話した？
意外と意地 悪いのな お前
You've got a surprising mean
streak in you, you know that?
Breaking up because with her, just
because of your father isn't good.
父親が原因で別れるなんて
よくないよ
Even breakups need
a good, solid reason.
別れるにしても
きちんとけじめつけて
何度も聞いたよ その話
I've heard that from you
a million times...
じゃあ 初めてする話
Then let's talk about
something new.
About Tanabe-san... Does she have
her eye on anyone in particular?
タナベさんって
決まった相手 いるのかな？
はあ？
あっ…
“お仕事 頑張って”か…
"Keep working hard," huh?
管制課に移動してもらう 係長だ
I'm going to transfer you to Control Section.
As the manager.
冗談 管制課なんて
Control Section?
You must be joking.
それも補佐とか すっ飛ばして
いきなり係長？
Plus, you'd make me manager, skipping over
being an assistant manager first?
私には現場が合ってるって
I belong out in
the field.
I want someone who knows
what it's like out there.
その現場を知る人間が欲しい
There's a limit to what
you can do out there.
現場でやれることには限界がある
だから 我々は
テクノーラ社にいるのだろう？
That's why we're in Technora,
isn't it?
（フィー）
テクノーラにいる理由ね
The reason we're in Technora, huh...
What is it again? I forget.
なんでだっけ？
Excuse me...
（タナベ）あの…
うっ ぐっ…
な… 何だ？ いきなり
Don't sneak up on me
like that!
あの… 教えてほしいことがあって
Um... I was hoping you could
tell me something.
Oh. I guess there are some things
you can't ask Hachi.
ああ…
ハチには聞けないこともあるよな
Actually...
その…
ギャハッ！
Who is having an affair
with whom?!
（フィー）誰が誰と
不倫してるって？ あん？
すいません すいません
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
I hear you've been asking around about me.
They said you were calling it networking.
あちこちに聞いて回ったそうだな
人脈とか言って
（ラビィ）私が全面的 全方位的
全力全開で悪うございました
In every way, shape, and form,
what I did was wrong!
（フィー）たく…
Geez, it's a sad story when the people
you work with don't trust you.
仲間に信じてもらえないなんて
情けない話だ
俺は別に…
（フィー）言い訳するな！
I didn't do anything.
Spare me the excuses!
（課長）んっ
タナベ てめえ！
Damn it, Tanabe!
Well, you guys were going around
with the wrong impression.
だって みんな勝手に勘違いして…
（ハチマキ）
だからって チクることねえだろ！
That doesn't mean you
should go squeal on us!
チクるって…
"Squeal" on you?
So anyway, what was it that you were
talking about with the division manager?
…で 結局 事業部長とは
何の話だったんですか？
ん？ ああ ただの昔話だよ
We were talking about the old days, that's all.
We were coworkers back in our old company.
同僚だからな 前の会社の
（ユーリ）え？
前の会社？
Old company?
あっ！ トラウム宇宙開発
Oh! Traum Space Development!
何です？ それ
What's that?
（ラビィ）昔 事業部長がつくった
ベンチャーだよ
A venture company the
division manager founded.
As I recall, it was acquired and absorbed
into Technora about 10 years ago...
確か 10年前に
うちに吸収合併されたんだっけ？
We all founded it together.
Dolf brought the four of us together.
みんなで つくったんだ
ドルフが
私たち４人を引っ張ってさ
We were small, but it was a great company
that pulled together like a family.
小さいけど―
みんな家族のようにまとまった
いい会社だった
いやあ 不倫じゃなくて
よかった よかった
Wow, I'm so relieved that it
wasn't an affair.
I can only hope that you refrain
from having any affairs, too, Ai-chan.
愛ちゃんも よろしくね
不倫は勘弁して
Senpai is the one you should
be saying that to, sir.
私より先輩に言ってください
Oh, he won't be a problem.
Women don't go for his type at all.
ああ こいつは大丈夫
女には 全然 モテないタイプだから
Actually, it looks like
he has a girlfriend.
先輩には 彼女がいるみたいですよ
Is that true, Hachi?!
そうなのか？ ハチ
Ha-chan, who is she?
I won't stand for any affairs, got it?
ハッちゃん 相手は誰？
不倫は困るよ 不倫は
いねえよ 彼女なんて
I don't have
a girlfriend.
病院でカードやってた子は？
Then what do you call that girl you were
playing cards with in the hospital?
What are you, nuts?
That girl's only 12 years old.
何言ってんだよ
あの子は まだ12歳だぞ
But she was taller
than you!
先輩より大きいのに？
Some 12 year olds
are like that.
いるんだよ そういう12歳も
ルナリアンじゃないんですか
Oh, she isn't a Lunarian,
is she?
ルナリアン？
Lunarian?
It means humans who were
born on the moon.
月で生まれた人間のことですよ
They grow extremely tall
as a result of the low gravity.
低重力なので 背が高くなるんです
へえ
じゃあ 体は大人なんだろ？
But she has the body
of an adult, right?
Stop talking like a pervert,
old man!
やらしい言い方すんな おやじ
Don't get so
worked up.
んな ムキになるなよ ん？
Why, hello there,
Chief Gehrhart.
（ラビィ）
これは これは ゲイハート課長
Has there been a change in plans
for the welcome reception?
歓迎会に何か変更点でも？
Don't try to pull any political
maneuvering with me.
（ゲイハート）
つまらない画策などするな
はっ？
Sir?
You came to me yesterday to ask
about the division manager.
（ゲイハート）昨日 私に
事業部長のことを聞きに来たな
（ラビィ）
ああ その件でしたら もう…
Oh, that! That's
all been sorted...
You wanted to show off that you have a
pipeline to the division manager, didn't you?
（ゲイハート）
事業部長とのパイプを―
誇示したかったというわけだな
あの… 私 そんな考えは何も
Um... The thought never
crossed my mind.
You don't know?
（ゲイハート）知らないのか？
（ラビィ）は？
Sir?
（ゲイハート）事業部長は
半課のフィー･カーマイケルを―
The division manager wants to assign Half
Section's Fee Carmichael to Control Section.
管制課に配属するつもりだ
I'm Section Chief there,
and he didn't even consult me.
課長の私に何の相談もなく
それも係長待遇でな
And he's going to make her
Assistant Chief, too!
か！？
（クレア）
Dbr-068-2114 通称“ゴースト”
Dbr-068-2114.
AKA "Ghost."
The debris is a special material
with stealth properties that was expelled from
an INTO lab module.
連合の実験モジュールから流出した
ステルス性の特殊素材です
レーダーには反応しない
It doesn't show up on radar. Which means that
we only have a rough idea of its position, right?
つまり 大ざっぱな位置しか
つかめないってことか
We'll give you an estimated position based on the
orbital data we collected while it was on dayside.
昼側の間につかんだ軌道データで
予測位置を出します
But you expect us to eyeball it when we're
making the retrieval itself, right?
でも 回収そのものは
目視でやれってことでしょ？
In addition, as you can see here, it expands
and becomes unstable at high temperatures.
（クレア）しかも
高温では このように―
膨張して
不安定な状態になります
So please carry out the retrieval on nightside,
where the temperatures are low.
ですから回収は―
低温になる夜側で
行ってください
It doesn't show up on radar, and you
can only catch it at night...
レーダーに映らない夜しか
捕まらない
It's just like a ghost,
all right.
まさしく ゴーストだね
Debris teams at other companies have
made several attempts to retrieve it,
他社のデブリ課が
なんとかトライしていますが―
...but they all ended
in failure.
全て失敗に終わっています
So if we can snag it,
we'll be heroes.
うちが拾えば ヒーローってわけだ
Provides a good excuse
for a promotion, too.
昇進もさせやすい… か
（ラビィ）フィーが係長…
Fee's gonna be a Manager...
And here I am, still only an Assistant Manager.
私だって まだ補佐なのに
別に おかしくはないでしょう？
That's hardly surprising,
though.
フィーさんが入社して10年―
What's strange is that Fee-san has been
with the company for ten years, and is still only
a crew leader.
今まで主任なのが
不思議なくらいですから
でも なんで
話してくれなかったんでしょうね？
But why didn't she say anything to us?
A promotion is a big deal.
せっかくの出世なのに
管制課が嫌なんじゃないかな
Maybe she hates the thought
of moving to Control Section.
Those guys are really tense
over there, you know?
ほら あそこって
なんか ピリピリしてるでしょ？
Oh! Maybe you're right!
（タナベ）あっ そうですね
ハッちゃんも嫌でしょ
いくら出世できるからって
You don't want to go there, either, right Ha-chan?
Even if it means being able to climb the ranks.
出世なんて
考えたこともないからな
I've never given much thought
to promotions and stuff.
It'd be okay if it meant getting your
own spaceship, though, right?
宇宙船が手に入るんなら
いいんじゃないですか？
Are you making fun
of me?
お前 バカにしてるだろ？
まっ 夢は人それぞれってことで
Well, we all have
our own dreams.
夢ねえ
We all have
dreams, huh?
Right! Yuri, will you act as pilot
on this new mission?
よし！ ユーリ
今回のミッション
パイロット やってくれるか？
えっ？ ああ
Sure.
タナベ 今日は俺たちだけで出るぞ
気合い 入れろ！
Tanabe, we're going out on our own today.
Give it everything you've got.
あっ はい
Um, okay.
Fee's thinking ahead for the times
when she won't be around.
フィーのやつ―
自分がいなくなったときのこと
考えてたんだよ
She wants to know if we can retrieve
debris by ourselves.
俺たちだけで
デブリを回収できるかって
はっ…
確かに
フィーさんがいないと困るねえ
We'd certainly be in a bind
without Fee-san...
だから 俺たちだけでやるんだよ
That's why we're going
to do this by ourselves.
We're gonna prove that we can still get the
job done even if she goes to Control Section!
フィーが管制課に行っても―
俺たちだけで
やっていけるって証明する！
（タナベ）先輩
Senpai!
If that's the case, I suppose
we have no choice.
（ユーリ）そういうことなら
しかたないですね
Manager, we'll leave the
arm control to you.
係長 アームのほう お願いします
（ラビィ）はあ？
You're qualified to run
an arm, aren't you?
（ハチマキ）
アーム操作資格 持ってんだろ？
Yes, on paper!
ペーパーなんだよ
Let's do it! This is a time for every
Debris Section worker to pull together!
やりましょう！
今こそ デブリ課全員が
力を合わせるときですよ
Right, Chief?!
ねっ 課長？
ええ！？ 僕も？
Me, too?
（クレア）では お願いします
事業部長も期待していますから
I'll let you get to it, then. The division
manager has a lot riding on this, too.
Yeah, yeah...
（フィー）はいはい
What's going on here?
Our great
division manager has left?
（ゲイハート）何だ 何だ
我らが事業部長は引き上げたのか
偉そうに もう重役のつもりか
Does he think he's on the Board of Directors
already, and he's too good for us?
（部下）
来客ですよ 連合から例の
He has a visitor.
That one from INTO.
ああ 引退する監査役に
ポストを世話しろってやつか
Oh, they must be forcing him to find a post
for that inspector who's retiring.
The managing director himself
is arranging it, so the division manager will
have no choice but to accept.
専務の口利きですからね
事業部長も
受け入れざるをえませんよ
フンッ
外様のくせに目立ち過ぎるから―
He's an outsider to begin with, so we get saddled
with baggage because he stands out from the crowd.
お荷物を押し付けられるんだ
半課とかな
Baggage like Half Section.
（フィー）んん… ふん！
（クレア）んっ…
うん？
Dolf, you dumb jerk...
（フィー）ドルフのバカ！
愚痴ぐらい言えってんだ
If you don't like something,
speak up, damn it!
（フィー）勝負は このゴーストが
夜側の軌道にいる45分間よ
We'll make our move in the 45 minute period
of the Ghost's orbit while it's on nightside.
During that time, we'll need to detect
the target visually and retrieve it.
その間に 目視で
ゴーストを発見して回収する
At that time, we...
このとき… ん？
なんか 今日は人が多いね
There sure are a lot of people
at the briefing today...
（ラビィ）ああ 一応
私はバックアップ要員だから
Well, I'm technically a backup
crew member, so...
Um, I have to understand the
work that my subordinates do.
（課長）ぶ… 部下の仕事は
把握しておかないとねえ
はあ？
いや ほら 管理職だし
何かとつきあいもねえ
Well, um, I'm management, right?
I need to act like I'm one of you.
D-Don't you worry about me.
Please continue.
うう… あんまり気にしないで
先に進めてくれないかな
Right! In this world, it's "You scratch
my back, and I'll scratch yours."
（ラビィ）そうそう 世の中
持ちつ持たれつって言うじゃない
（電話の着信音）
（フィー）ん？
O-Oh, I guess we have
a phone call.
（電話の着信音）
（課長）で… 電話かなあ？
Hello, this is Debris Section.
（エーデル）はい デブリ課です
Yes, sir. I understand.
I'll pass that along.
はい 分かりました 伝えます
フィーさん 管制課から―
Fee-san, it's Control Section.
They've pushed
back the mission by six hours.
今回のミッション
６時間遅れになるそうです
Six hours, huh?
Okay, understood.
６時間ね 分かった
Why don't you use the time
to get a little sleep?
みんなで昼寝
（フィー）はあ？
Everyone should
take a nap!
いい提案だと思います
I think that's a good suggestion.
Concentration will be vital for this mission.
今回の仕事は
集中力が必要ですから
賛成
（タナベ）うんうん
I agree.
まあ いいけど
Well, if you insist...
This is an official announcement.
（専務）今日は
有意義な話ができて よかった
I'm glad we were able to have such
a productive discussion today.
All supervisors of 7th and 9th bay operations,
please report to the Bay Office.
では あとのことは頼んだよ
ドルフ君
Well, I'll leave the matter
in your hands, Dolf-kun.
I'll take care of everything,
Managing Director.
お任せください 専務
I repeat...
Right.
（専務）ああ
All supervisors of 7th and 9th
bay operations, please report...
（ドルフ）寄生虫が…
You damn parasite...
Anyway, we need to get this finished
while Fee-kun is still asleep!
（ラビィ）ともかく フィー君が
寝ている間に片づけないと
We've been looking,
but there's no sign of it...
（タナベ）
さっきから探してるんですけどね
Are you sure the orbit calculations
aren't wrong?
（ハチマキ）
軌道計算 間違えてんじゃねえの？
（課長）でも
モニターに映らないんでしょ？
It doesn't show up on our
monitors, though, right?
（ユーリ）いえ
レーダーに映りにくいだけで―
No. It's nearly invisible on radar,
but it can be seen with the naked eye.
物体として 目で確認可能です
…にしたって暗すぎてさあ
Maybe, but it's too dark
out there!
But it turns all gooey
in daylight...
でも 昼だと グニャグニャに
なっちゃうんですよね
（社員１）
どういうことだよ ドルフ！
What's going on here, Dolf?!
Join Technora?!
Are you kidding me?!
（社員２）テクノーラに入るなんて
冗談じゃないわ！
Is it true, Dolf?!
（フィー）本当なの？ ドルフ
（社員たち）ドルフ ドルフ！
Dolf!
- Dolf!
I'm sorry, everyone...
（ドルフ）すまん みんな
すまん
I'm sorry.
くっそ
変なこと思い出しちまった
Crap... Why did I have to go
dredge up that memory?
ああ もう 寝てられるか
こんなときに
Damn it, how can they expect me
to sleep at a time like this?!
I see it!
（課長）あっ あった！
（ハチマキ）
だから ありゃ セブンだって
I keep telling you,
that's Seven.
It's over there!
（ラビィ）こっちにあるぞ
That's the D4
experiment module.
（ユーリ）
Ｄ４の実験モジュールです
じゃあ あっちのは？
What about that, then?!
手当たりしだいに言えば
いいってもんじゃないだろ？
Pointing at every little thing
you see isn't helping!
いや それです
No, actually, that's it.
You're kidding!
Wow, he's right!
（タナベ）あっ 本当だ
It isn't showing up on radar,
just like the file says, so this is it.
（ユーリ）
資料のとおり レーダーには―
何も映っていませんから
こいつです
I was the one who found it?
Really?!
僕が見つけたの？ ほんと？
That's our Chief!
Nicely done!
さすがは課長 お見事です
（課長）うんうん…
よーし 行くぞ タナベ
あと 30分っきゃないんだから
Okay, Tanabe, let's get to it!
We have less than 30 minutes.
Right.
はい
（ラビィ）待て ハチ！
Hold it, Hachi!
ん？
Don't forget that you're a company man.
It's your superiors who give the orders!
自分がサラリーマンだってことを
忘れるなよ
命令するのは
上司に決まってるだろ！
さあ 課長
（課長）うん
Give the word, Chief.
Right!
Launch the Fishbone!
フィッシュボーン 発進！
（ハチマキ）
無駄な時間 使わせんなって
Stop wasting our time,
damn it!
Dolf... Being by yourself
is tough, isn't it?
（フィー）
ドルフ １人はつらいよね
（デボン）あ… あれ？
What in the world?
What, did you come by to drop off
your ferret again?
（フィー）何？
また フェレット 預けに来たの？
Um, yes, but...
ええ あっ でも…
Is everybody still
out napping?
みんな まだ昼寝してるのかな？
あの… フィーさん 病気じゃ…
Um, I thought you
were sick, Fee-san...
はあ？
（エーデル）チェッ
Damn.
（ハチマキ）
レンズは光学探知にしてるよな？
You have your lenses set on
optical detection, right?
Yes.
（タナベ）はい でも―
But I didn't expect that making a naked-eye
approach would be this hard.
目視で接近するのが
こんなに大変なんて
まだ ずれてます
ピッチアップ２度 ヨーライト５度
We're drifting again. Pitch up 2 degrees
Yaw right 5 degrees.
Once we get those beacons attached,
it'll be as good as ours.
（ハチマキ）信号さえ取り付ければ
こっちのもんだけど
夜時間終了まで
20分を切りました
You have less than 20 minutes
until nightside exit.
DS-12, report your situation.
DS-12 状況を報告してください
ToyBoxが出てる？
Toy Box has left
the station?!
（デボン）
いや フィーさん 急病だって
T-They said that you came
down with something!
うっ…
すてきなノーラ君グッズね
エーデル
Gosh, that's a fine Nora pendant
that you have there, Edel.
Thank you.
はい
Senpai! I'm all done
over here!
先輩 こっち終わりましたけど
Same here. Yuri, patch the signal
through to Control Section!
（ハチマキ）こっちもだ
ユーリ
管制課と通信をつないでくれ
We have a lock
on the Ghost!
ゴーストを捉えました… はっ
Orbital deviation detected. Nightside exit
in 15 minutes, 24 seconds.
軌道誤差を確認
夜時間終了まで 15分24秒
How long?! You were off
by more than two minutes?!
何！？
２分も誤差があったってのか？
Manager, please pull it inside the cargo
container with the manipulator arm.
係長 アームで
コンテナの中に入れ込んでください
係長？
Manager?
I know, I know!
Don't rush me!
（ラビィ）
分かってるから せかさないで！
バランスを取って
えぐりこむように
Keep your balance.
Use a scooping motion...
そうだ 行け！
That's the way!
Go!
（タナベ･ハチマキ）ああ…
（ハチマキ）行き過ぎだって
You overshot it,
damn it!
あ… あれえ？
Huh? Oh, dear...
んんっ… 戻ってくれー！
Come back!
あれ？
What the...?
We just generated some
secondary debris.
（ユーリ）
２次デブリが発生してしまいました
（課長）どうしよう
What do we
do now?
They said they were going
to do it without you.
フィーさん抜きでやるそうですよ
（フィー）ん？
Isn't this good news?
よかったですね
Control Section is more secure than retrieving
debris, and you get a pay bump, too.
管制課なら デブリ回収より
安全だし 給料も上がるし
Those little twerps...
あいつら
（管制官）ハァ… やはり 駄目
（クレア）ええ
No good, huh?
Yes.
This is Seven. We'll let another company
deal with the secondary debris.
こちらセブン
２次デブリは 他社に任せます
ゴーストも
船長の体調が万全なときの―
I recommend that you make another try for
the Ghost once your captain is back at 100%.
リトライを勧めますが？
Uh, about that...
それは…
No, we'll do it!
（ハチマキ）いや やる
（ユーリ）ん…
We still have a signal lock, right?!
We know where it is!
信号は生きてるんだろ？
位置は分かってんだ！
（タナベ）ああっ…
（ハチマキ）ラビィ
つかみやすい所まで押し込む
Lavie! I'm gonna push it to where
you can reach it easier!
Do it right this time!
今度はしっかりやってくれよ
I keep trying to tell you that
I'm only qualified on paper!
だからさ
ペーパーだって言ってるじゃない
Of course I can't do this!
無理に決まってるって
What's with that talk?! If we give up, we won't
be able to look Fee in the eye when she leaves!
（ハチマキ）何言ってんだ！
諦めたりしたら どの面下げて
フィーを送り出せってんだよ
We're gonna get the job done
by ourselves this time!
今回は
俺たちだけで やってみせるんだ
もう～
わあ！
You did it!
You lucked out!
（ハチマキ）
やったな ハハッ すっげえ偶然！
係長 そのまま引き寄せてくだ…
Okay, Manager,
now bring it...
係長 そのまま引き寄せてくだ…
（警告音）
あっ しまった
Oh, no!
やっべえ
Oh, crap!
What the hell were those
morons thinking?!
（フィー）
何考えてんだ あのバカどもが！
（クレア）うっ… 信号が離れる
The beacons are breaking loose! It's the
same mistake the other teams made!
他のチームと同じミスを…
DS-12!
Report your situation!
DS-12 状況を報告してください
We can't get a clear read
on the Ghost from here!
こちらでは
ゴーストの状態を把握しきれません
Come in, Seven.
This is DS-12.
（ユーリ）セブンへ こちらDS-12
ゴーストが液状化
本船のＥＶＡ要員２名が―
The Ghost has liquefied, swallowing up two
of our EVA crew along with their work craft.
回収作業艇とともに
ゴーストに取り込まれました
駄目だ こんなグニャグニャ
つかめないよ
It's no use! I can't get
a grip on this goop!
Hey! What's it...
（タナベ）先輩 ああっ
（ハチマキ）
タナベ 不用意に動くな
水中訓練を思い出せ！
Tanabe! Don't make any
careless movements!
Remember your
underwater training!
At this rate, it's going to drift farther
and farther off its estimated orbit...
このままでは 計算軌道から
どんどんずれてしまう
Can't we rescue them?
Hey, can't we rescue them?!
助からないの？
ねえ 助からないの？ ユーちゃん
Yuri-chan!
私が外に出ます
ToyBoxの操縦 お願いします
I'm going outside.
You have control of Toy Box.
ちょ ちょっと 無理だよ
僕は車のハンドルだって―
W-Wait, I can't do that! My wife doesn't even
let me get behind the wheel of a car!
妻に握らして
もらえないくらいなんだよ
She doesn't even let me
drive used cars!
中古車だって
許してもらえないんだ
しかし このままでは…
- But if we don't do something,
they'll...
Yuri, get back
in your seat!
（フィー）ユーリ 席に戻って
（ユーリ）なっ
（課長）えっ
（ハチマキ）フィーか
Is that Fee?
あなた 急病だったんじゃ…
I thought you were sick!
軌道方向 微速前進
秒 12メートル 増速
Move slowly ahead along your trajectory.
Accelerate 12 meters per second.
Move ahead of the Ghost and use
Toy Box to cast a shadow.
一旦 ゴーストを追い越して
ToyBoxで影を作って
そうか
旧式のToyBoxは大きいから
Right! An old ship like
Toy Box is huge!
It should be plenty big enough
to cover the Ghost.
（フィー）
十分 ゴーストを覆いきれるはずよ
（タナベ）でも そうすると
縮んじゃいますよね？ これ
But it'll shrink when you
do that, won't it?!
（フィー）心配するな
デブリ回収用のスーツだろ
Don't worry, those are debris recovery suits.
The specs say we'll be able to handle it.
データ上は耐えられる
The important thing is for you and Hachi
to move to the Ghost's edge.
それより
ハチとタナベは ゴーストの端に
Stick as much as you can outside the Ghost
while it's liquefied, even if it's just your left arms.
液状になってる間に
左腕だけでも 外に出すんだ
Right. Can you do that,
Tanabe?
（ハチマキ）
よし できるな？ タナベ
（タナベ）はい
Yes.
Lavie, put the arm in a horizontal position.
Increase the shadow area as much as possible.
（フィー）
ラビィは アームを横位置に
少しでも影面積を取って
分かりました
Understood!
（フィー）最後に課長
（課長）はい
And last comes you, Chief.
Yes?
（フィー）何もしないで
（課長）アイ コピー
Don't do anything.
I copy!
船長は代理なんですよ？
できると思っているんですか？
The man at the helm is just a stand-in!
Do you really think he can do this?
Even if you're in Control Section, you're still
part of the debris recovery team.
管制課ではあっても―
あなたも
デブリ回収チームの仲間でしょ？
はあ？
If you don't believe in your teammates,
you'll never get anywhere.
仲間を信じなきゃ
何も始まらないって
（クレア）あ…
Wow, that was close!
危ねえ ギリッギリ
タナベは？
What about you,
Tanabe?!
I'm sorry, I wasn't
able to make it out!
（タナベ）すいません
出られませんでした
ハチ 重心方向に 10秒噴射
- Hachi!
Fire a ten-second thrust
along your center of gravity!
（ハチマキ）あいよ
You got it!
（フィー）
ラビィ アームで押し込みな
Lavie, try pushing it in
with the arm!
（ラビィ）は… はい
Y-Yes, ma'am!
Switch channel G8
back to auto.
（フィー）
チャンネルＧ８ オートで戻す
（ラビィ）はい
Yes, ma'am!
ＯＫ そのまま引っ張り込んで
ユーリ コンテナを閉じる
Okay, keep pulling
it towards you.
Yuri! Close the
cargo container!
Understood.
（ユーリ）分かりました
And... okay!
Retrieval complete!
よーし 回収完了
We did it!
やったー！
成功したの？ 成功したの？
Did we do it?
ハッハー！ 幽霊を捕まえましたよ
この私たちが
We caught that boogie man!
We caught it!
よかった 本当に
Thank goodness...
（ハチマキ）おーい
Hey!
コンテナ内の温度上げてくれよ
動けないんだよ
Raise the temperature in the
cargo container! I can't move!
（管制官たちのざわめき）
みんな 気を抜くのは まだ早いよ
It's too early to start celebrating
just yet, people.
A debris hauler's job isn't done
until it's hauled back to base.
デブリを持ち帰るまでが
デブリ屋の仕事だからね
ユー コピー？
You copy?
We copy!
（ハチマキたち）ウィ コピー
Hey, Tanabe, you okay?
（ハチマキ）
おい タナベ 大丈夫か？
Yes, I think.
（タナベ）はい なんとか
（ハチマキ）
シャッキリしろ！ 俺たちは―
Look sharp!
We grabbed the Ghost, a piece of debris
that no other debris section could catch.
よそのデブリ屋が拾えなかった
ゴーストを捕まえたんだぞ！
はい でも…
（ハチマキ）ああ？
Yes, but...
This means that Fee-san's
gonna leave, isn't it?
これで フィーさん
行っちゃうんですね
（ハチマキ）あっ…
Yeah, I guess it does.
ああ そうだな
（管制官）EBR-068-2114R…
DBR-068-2114
is extremely...
So, I hear you had to hire
a retired INTO bureaucrat, huh?
（フィー）聞いたわ 連合から
天下りを受け入れるんだって？
If you consider the big picture,
it ends up as a plus for us.
（ドルフ）
トータルで考えれば プラスになる
You're not happy
with it?
気に入らないか？
（フィー）そうね
I guess not.
だから 栄転を辞退したのか？
That's why you turned down
the promotion?
No, it's not. I want to stay
out in the field, that's all.
違うわ 私は現場にいたいだけ
（ドルフ）我々の生活は
今更 後戻りはできない
There's no turning back from
humanity's new way of life.
And we have to rely on space for the
energy to support that way of life.
そして そのためのエネルギーは
宇宙に頼るしか すべがない
Space development requires
that you work on a large scale.
宇宙開発には スケールが必要だ
Funding. Organization. Political clout.
資金 組織 政治力
それがなければ
別の何かに飲み込まれる
Without those, you get
swallowed up by another entity.
Just like our
company did?
（フィー）私たちの会社みたいに？
（ドルフ）だから 我々は
変わらなければならない
That is why we
have to change.
You. And me.
君も 私も
フッ…
Dolf, you haven't
changed one bit.
ドルフ あなたは変わっていないわ
Yes, I have.
変わったさ
（フィー）
変わったように見えるだけ
You only look like
you've changed.
Spend some time in the sun, and you'll
turn back into your old self.
光を浴びれば すぐに元に戻るわ
私は 今もあなたと
チームを組んでるつもりよ
I like to think that you and I
are still on the same team.
光の当たる場所まで
早く駆け上がって
Claw your way back up into the light.
Back to where you can be yourself again.
あなたが
元の姿を取り戻せる場所まで
そうなれば 私も安心して働ける
Do that, and I'll be able to do my job
with some peace of mind.
ねっ？
Right?
うん
フッ… ユー コピー？
You copy?
♪～
♪グッと水を飲み干し
gutto mizu wo nomihoshi
We gulp down some water
♪夕焼け雲見上げるのさ
yuuyakegumo miageru no sa
and look up at the evening clouds.
♪今日も一日が終わって
kyou mo ichinichi ga owatte
Let's wind our way home under the roadside trees as another day ends.
♪街路樹の下を帰ろう
gairoju no shita wo kaerou
♪やることだらけで
テンパって、
yaru koto darake de tenpatte
Even if life's so hectic that our tempers flare,
♪無理をして、
つまずいても
muri wo shite tsumazuite mo
we push ourselves too hard, and we stumble,
♪何か必ず
つかんでるさ
nani ka kanarazu tsukanderu sa
I know there'll be something to grab hold of.
♪気楽にいこうぜ
kiraku ni ikou ze
Let's move on without a care in our hearts.
♪素晴らしい人生だから
subarashii jinsei dakara
It's a wonderful life.
♪自分を愛する
勇気を持とう
jibun wo aisuru yuuki wo motou
So let's have the courage to love ourselves.
♪新しいドア叩いて
atarashii doa tataite
Let's take it one step at a time,
♪ひとつひとつ
歩いてゆこう
hitotsu hitotsu aruite yukou
knocking on new doors on the way.
♪素晴らしい人生なのさ
subarashii jinsei na no sa
It's a wonderful life.
♪君も僕もすべての人も
kimi mo boku mo subete no hito mo
You and I and everyone else
♪喜びと悲しみの意味
yorokobi to kanashimi no imi
Keep on searching for the meaning
♪探しつづけて
so just on my way
sagashitsuzukete so just on my way
Of joy and sadness, so just on my way.
Next Time
Regrets
Gigalt Gungulgash of the
Orbital Security Agency.
（ギガルト）
軌道保安庁の―
ギガルト･
ガンガラガッシュだ
この～
Why, you...!
んぐぅ…
（ハチマキ）うわーっ
ぷはー
（リュシー）タナベ！
Tanabe!
その日は予定が入ってて
I have plans
that day.
（ハチマキ）そっか
Oh, I see.
（ギガルト）野菜を取れと
何度 言ったら分かるんだ
How many times do I have to tell you
to eat your veggies?!
ん…
What's with you? You got a problem with it?
何だよ
何か文句でもあるのか？
じゃあ 違うんですか？
You think I'm wrong?
（ハチマキ）
どっちでもいいだろ？
It doesn't matter
either way, right?
（ギガルト）ハチマキ！
（ラビィ）ご覧くださーい
Hachimaki!
Take a look... at these!